<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Plants et al. on Alex Ledger</title>
    <link>/plants/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Plants et al. on Alex Ledger</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/plants/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Updates - May 12, 2019</title>
      <link>/plants/updates-may-12-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 May 2019 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/plants/updates-may-12-2019/</guid>
      <description>Fermentation - Sauerkraut Cat and I made a few batches of Sauerkraut over the last few weeks. It was super easy and delicious. We used a combination of the recipes found in Real Food Fermentation: Preserving Whole Fresh Food with Live Cultures in Your Home Kitchen by Alex Lewan and The Noma Guide to Fermentation, with help on some of the physical, technical tasks from Brad Leone&amp;rsquo;s videos.
One issue we ran into with the batch above was that we over-seasoned.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Growing Basil Starters</title>
      <link>/plants/growing-basil-starters/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2019 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/plants/growing-basil-starters/</guid>
      <description>Cat and I finished setting up our grow lights two and a half weeks. Our lights are Sunleaves Pioneer VI High-output T5 4 Foot lights (Fluorescent T5) which are raised with a Jump Start 4 Foot light stand.
We planted Genovese basil as our first endeavor. We three pot-like items, added soil, and sprinkled the seeds uniformly on top of the soil. Based on what we online, basil seeds can be placed on top of soil (i.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Our Growing Space</title>
      <link>/plants/our-growing-space/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Feb 2019 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/plants/our-growing-space/</guid>
      <description>Want to give a quick introduction to the growing space that we are working with. My partner Cat and I rent an apartment in Somerville, Massachusetts. We live with two cats and grow most of our plants in our spare room that we only let the cats in if we are around (because they love munching on the plants).
Our spare room has a small south-facing window that directly faces another building.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Furb-Sust</title>
      <link>/plants/furb-sust/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Dec 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/plants/furb-sust/</guid>
      <description>In August 2018 I embarked on a project focused on developing skills for refurbishing items and improving my personal sustainability practices to reduce my and my community’s wastefulness. I designed this activity around ideas in Jane Mcgonigal’s Superbetter. The premise is that a game-ful mindset helps people find meaning, achieve their goals, be happier, and be better contributors to their community.
Using Mcgonigal’s framework I identified my epic win as:</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>