<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Homes on Alex Ledger</title>
    <link>/home/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Homes on Alex Ledger</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 02 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/home/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/home/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/home/about/</guid>
      <description>Email: a.led1027 &amp;lt;at&amp;gt; gmail &amp;lt;dot&amp;gt; com Github: github.com/aled1027 I am a technologist and plant enthusiast. If you are interested in learning more about my projects with plants, check out my plant blog.
I currently work at Cambridge Semantics as a Senior Field Architect where I combine data science, data engineering, software architecture, consulting, and business analytics to support our data product in customers&#39; environments.
I used to work in the Secure Resilient Systems and Technology Group at MIT Lincoln Lab, where my team built a programming framework for secure multi-party computation (MPC) protocols.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interests and Technologies</title>
      <link>/home/technologies/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/home/technologies/</guid>
      <description>Interests         Data analysis, Data Visualization, Graph databases, Machine Learning   Cryptography, Computer Security, Privacy, Anonymity    Technologies          Languages C, C++, Python, JavaScript, Java, Rust, Haskell, Clojure, Coq, Latex   Data analysis and visualization Python, JavaScript, R, Octave, Mathematica, Matlab   Databases SQL, NoSQL, Graph databases, SPARQL   Cloud AWS, Google Cloud Platform, Linux, Bash, Git    </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Work and Projects</title>
      <link>/home/projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/home/projects/</guid>
      <description>Plants I am currently working on a variety of projects involving plants. Check out my plant blog to learn more!
Framework for Efficient Development of Secure Multi-party Computation At MIT Lincoln Lab, I work on a team designing and developing a framework for secure multi-party computation (MPC) protocols. MPC is a privacy-enhancing, cryptographic technique for securely computing functions on private data - that is, the inputs and all intermediate values are never revealed to anyone.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
