<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Homes on Alex Ledger</title>
    <link>/home/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Homes on Alex Ledger</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 02 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/home/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/home/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/home/about/</guid>
      <description>Email: a.led1027 &amp;lt;at&amp;gt; gmail &amp;lt;dot&amp;gt; com Github: github.com/aled1027  I am a cryptography software developer in the Resilient Systems and Technology Group at MIT Lincoln Lab, where I am building a programming framework for secure multi-party computation (MPC) protocols.
Before coming to MIT Lincoln Lab I was an undergraduate at Reed College studying Mathematics and Computer Science. I wrote my thesis on secure two-party computation and Yao&amp;rsquo;s garbled circuits under the supervision of Dr.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Work and Projects</title>
      <link>/home/projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/home/projects/</guid>
      <description>Framework for Efficient Development of Secure Multiparty Computation At MIT Lincoln Lab, I am designing and developing an MPC framework for secure multiparty computation. More information to come.
Externally Verifiable Oblivious Random Access Memory Oblivious Random Access Memory (ORAM) protocols are cryptographic protocols for obscuring a client&amp;rsquo;s access patterns to a set of data. In this project, we extended existing ORAM protocols to suppport a public, external party (e.g., a friend, paid contractor, or smart contract on a blockchain) to verify that the client and server are adhering to the protocol.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>